Within loops, there may be a time in which
you need to have a condition for exiting a
loop early. Using the previous code example
as a guide, I have added a platinum coin
to a player's list of coins. Players collect
coins by answering questions correctly. They
are automatically moved to the next level if they
obtain a platinum coin. Thus, we want this code,
the 223-break file, to stop and print a different
message if the player gets a platinum coin. I will
add an if statement on line 4 to see if the
coin is Platinum. Remember that criteria are
case-sensitive. I will then indent line 5 and add
a congratulatory print statement. The new keyword,
break, I will add to line 6. Break exits
a loop. We are saying logically here that
if a player obtains a platinum coin, no other
coins matter as the player automatically gets
moved to the next level. Here is a question:
how many statements do you think will print
when we run this code? Let’s find out. The
code prints four statements. The first three
statements represent getting through the
first three coins in the coins tuple. Then,
being that the third coin is platinum, the
congratulatory statement prints, and then,
because of the break line, the loop ends before
it gets to the gold coin. The real-life gaming
application is that the gold coin is irrelevant
after the platinum coin and thus does not need
to be displayed. Break statements break out of
loops when required and prevent one from adding
multiple conditional statements to break out of a
loop, saving time and potential errors in logic.